Guide to the William Wolf collection of Buckminster Fuller papers pertaining to the World Game and Design Science Institute M1684
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William Wolf collection of Buckminster Fuller papers pertaining to the World Game and Design Science Institute
1940-1992
M1684
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
4.0 Linear feet 8 manuscript boxes
Letters, memos, and reports, including several items signed and/or annotated by Fuller. Also assorted pamphlets, posters, newspaper and magazine articles, photographs, slides, and ephemera. 24 tapes and transcripts containing conversation between Buckminster Fuller, William Wolf, Neva Kaiser, Michael Ben-Eli, and Robert Brooks discussing Fuller's vision for the World Game.
Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983
Wolf, William
Acquisition Information
This collection [was purchased by OR given by NAME HERE to] Stanford University, Special Collections in MONTH YEAR.
Publication Rights
No restrictions.
Scope and Contents note
Materials are listed at folder level.
- William Wolf manuscript material, 3.5 Linear feet
  - Fortune Article on US Industrialization with data by RBF (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Dymaxion Air-Ocean World Map (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - TEMCOR Geodesic dome brochure (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Guardian Article by Dennis Barker signed by RBF (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - TIME cover story (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Saturday Review: "The Prospect for Humanity" (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Esquire: "Instant Slum Clearance" (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - St. Louis Post Dispatch: The Case for a Domed City (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - New Yorker profile (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "How Little I Know" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Washington Post article regarding RBF (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Saturday Review: "What Have I Learned" (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Article in Saturday Review of Literature (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NY Times: "An Expo Named Buckminster Fuller" (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - List of RBF publications (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Saturday Review Article: "What I am trying to do" (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Saturday Review: "Goddesses of the 21st Century" (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Saturday Review: "The Age of Astro Architecture" (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arch. Env. Health: "What Quality of Environment Do We Want?" (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - HUD report re. poor (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes from RBF lecture (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - World Game memo (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - St. Louis Globe article re. World Game and SIU (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Article: "Inside Bucky's Head" (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Reader's Digest: "Meet Bucky Fuller" (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dimensions and Definitions of Man & Earth (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - San Francisco Express Times article re. RBF (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Futuristic Article: Fuller's floating city (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Entering the Age of the Unspecialist" (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - US Congress World Game presentation, signed by RBF (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Transcript of Today Show interview with RBF (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Invitation to Talk at American Astronautical Society mtg. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letter re. ORSA/AAS meeting (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Re. ORSA/AAS meeting (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letter re. ORSA/AAS meeting in Denver (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - World Game comment, rough draft (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - World Game speech at Astronautics Conference (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Invitation to Attend World Game Seminar in NY City (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "World Game Report" by RBF and Ed Schlossberg (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Pace Magazine article re. RBF (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - T. Turner letter re. World Game (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Wolf Computer Corp World Game proposal to SIU (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - World Game Report (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Wolf letter re. design science institute (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Ed Applewhite resume (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - World Game Newsletter #1 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - World Game Extension Study Centers (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Geodesic Domes Brochure (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Package for respondents to Saturday Review Ad (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Dymaxion World Map ad (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - World game facility (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - NY Times article on scientific advance (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - SIU purchase order (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - IBM/MIT proposal for Urban Housing Computer Model (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - World Game - State of the Art Report (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - RBF article in Saturday Review (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Letter from F. Waner to W. Wolf re. Nobel Peace Prize Nomination (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Dwayne Hendrick's World Game memo (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "Preamble" re. World Game (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Report & proposal - World Game Simulation Tool (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Introductory letter from L. Hales to W. Wolf (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Letter from R. Frenchman to W. Wolf re. computer use for World Game (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - World Game computer effort photos (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - World Game effort final report (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "Hydroponics" (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Draft of Nobel Peace Prize letter (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Hymn - Lord of All Hopefulness (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Article re. Bucky's views on television (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - "User's Guide for Fuller - Percap" (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Personal letter from R.B. Fuller to W. Wolf (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Business Week article re. Club of Rome (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Fuller - Percap user's update (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Lord's Prayer - 2nd version (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Foreign aid (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Design Science Institute information packet (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - "4 D Time Lock" (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Architectural Forum - The World of Buckminster Fuller (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Harry Nilsson song book (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - World Game proposal (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Letter from H. Wolf re. DSI (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - NY Times: New Institute (DSI) to Promote RBF's Pioneer Ideas (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Letter from H. Wolf and press release re. Walter Hickel (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Minutes of the annual meeting of the DSI (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Resume re. Richard Hyde (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Report of Ad Hoc Subcomittee of the DSI (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Article re. consultants counting staff (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Notes from meeting in Philadelphia (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - "Buckminster Fuller Retrospective" (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Earth Metabolic Design Workbook (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Memo regarding meeting with Ben-Eli, Schlossberg & O'Reagan (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Fuller Earth Projection (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - DSI: operations & prospects (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - P. Schwartz address (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Ad regarding unified field (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Pages from Earth, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Design Science Institute description (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Letter from H. Wolf to DSI re. Saturday Evening Post & Time re. Bucky (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Saturday Evening Post article - "Fuller's Earth" (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Notes on DSI meeting in Philadelphia (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Invitation to workshop (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Letter from B. O'Reagan to N. Kaiser re. activities at Stanford University (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Letter from E. Hauben to N. Kaiser re. World Game (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Letter from B. O'Reagan to N. Kaiser re. activities at Stanford University (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Letter from H. Wolf to R.B. Fuller re. Herman Wolf & DSI & resignation (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Letter from G. Youngbloo to R.B. Fuller re. DSI grant (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to W. Wolf re. RBF conversation (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Notes on DSI meeting in Philadelphia (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Introduction to R.B. Fuller (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Article regarding Global Economics (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - World Game Science Center timetable (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Letter from R. Whaley to W. Wolf et. al. re. Whaley's activities (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Regarding Leontief's Input-Output Matrix (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to W. Wolf (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - R.B. Fuller basic biography (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to R.B. Fuller re. World Game (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Employment correspondence from R. Brooks (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Proposal for development of a World Energy Scenario (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - H. Carroll resume (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - "Energy Through Wind Power" (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - World Game proposal (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Energy flow (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - World Game notes (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - "Better News" extracted from "Nine Chains to the Moon" (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Negative of Dymaxion Projection of Globe (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Sketch of data collection re. people (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - "Design Science Primer" by Earth Metabolic Design (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - World Game & Design Science descriptions (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - "Design Science & the DSI" memo (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Prop. - World Energy Scenario as prototype World Game operation (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Life: R.B. Fuller on spaceship Earth (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Forum article re. World Game at Studio School (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Model of Dymaxion Sky-Ocean World Game (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Now House - introduction (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser re. funding (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - re. ISHI Research Center (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - World Game Proposal - 2nd draft (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Memo re. revised budget (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to W. Dietel re. World Game proposal (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - World Game proposal letter (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - World Game Study proposal acceptance & related letters (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to DSI re. World Game proposal (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to U. Thant re. World Game proposal (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Copyright claim of World Game proposal - Kaiser & Wolf (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Popular Science article re. satellite pictures (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Agenda for DSI Philadelphia meeting (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Definition of World Game (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Letter from G. Olds to W. Wolf re. meetings (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Letter from R.B. Fuller to J. Clinton re. World Game & other matters (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - DSI Employment Agreement (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Article re. "World's Resources Dwindling" (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - "Set-Theoretic View of Data-Base Representation" by H. Beitz (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Introduction to meditation & stress (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Earth Metabolic Design report (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - World Game preliminary concepts & physical arrangement (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Outline of final World Game report (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to R.B. Fuller re. World Game (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - DSI letter re. Beitz paper (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - re. World Game (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Earth Metabolic Design ads (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - World Game studies workshop by Earth Metabolic Design (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Letter from B. Hubbard to W. Wolf re. Committee for the Future (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - re. UNU Inst. on Energy Progress Report (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Boston Globe: editorial re. One World (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Bank Note (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - re. DSI meeting in Aspen (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - "Mass Attraction" Ballet (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - DSI budgetary needs (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Minutes of DSI annual meeting (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Scribe's notes re. DSI annual meeting (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Minutes of Board meeting in Aspen (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - DSI statement of purpose (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Minutes of Design Science Institute meeting in Aspen (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Transcription of World Game tapes - R.B. Fuller (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Letter from G. Dickler to W. Wolf re. loan (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to H. Wolf re. tape (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to N. Kaiser re. proposal (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Grand strategy of world problem solving (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Article - computer model of world food supply (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - re. change from R. Brooks to M. Ben-Eli as researcher (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - World Game agreement (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Notes from NYC meeting with M. Ben-Eli (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Letters from E. Applewhite to W. Wolf re. energy crisis and M. Ben-Eli (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - MENSA Journal presidential address (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Letter from R.B. Fuller to M. McLuhan re. pollution (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Beitz correspondence (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Synergistics notes (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Meeting notes (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - "The Design Science Institute" copyright (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Report re. Philadelphia work (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to G. Olds re. DSI (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Letter from B. Willard to W. Wolf re. Fuller invitation (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Article re. J.D. Rockefeller (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Papers re. report to Rockefeller Brother's Fund (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - "Steps to World Game" (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Final report on World Game study (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Letter from W. Dietel to W. Wolf re. receipt of World Game study final report (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Minutes of special meeting of the Design Science Board (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Saturday Review World Game ad (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - J. Knowles article (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - DSI ad (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Saturday Review DSI ad copy (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - DSI minutes - October 14, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - DSI foreign advisors (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Futures Lab announcement (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - "Remapping Our World" - article in Today's Education (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - W. Wolf speech at Franklin Pierce College (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Letters from W. Wolf re. Maria Applewhite (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - World Game letter (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - "Steps to World Game" copyright (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - re. DSI & UN University (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - A A U N Status (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - re. DSI Registration with NY State Board of Social Welfare (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - re. American Association for the United Nations University (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - re. DSI & UN University (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - re. DSI Board (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - re. UN University & World Game (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - DSI Matters (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - DSI Matters (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - DSI letter from N. Kaiser to DSI Board (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - Proxy for DSI meetings (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - Report of Rockefeller Brother's Fund meeting in NYC (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - "What I am trying to do" (Box 6, Folder 222)
  - DSI agenda (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - re. UN University project (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - DSI & World Game funding (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - "Set-Theoretic View of Data-Base Representation" by Beitz (Box 6, Folder 226)
  - 100-word expression of "What I am trying to do" (Box 6, Folder 227)
  - re. Loeb proposal - including Loeb proposal (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - re. "Mass Attraction" (Box 6, Folder 229)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to G. Olds re. DSI funding (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - "Design Science and the DSI" - brochure (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Proposed chart of flow of funds & letter to YPO members (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - Proposal for development of a World Energy Scenario (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Memo re. World Game (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - "The Dynamics of Global Stability" proposed project (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - UNU Project (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Notes re. funding sources (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - Howard Brown resume (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - Charts re. Global Energy Study (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - State of UNU report (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - re. Design Science Institute Federal Income Tax Return (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Remarks after dinner to honor UNU new Rector J. Hestor (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Letters from J. Toll to W. Wolf re. SUNY & DSI collaboration (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - World Game correspondence (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - Notes re. UNU rules re. deductibility (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - DSI Logo (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - UNU - Christian Science Article (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to R.B. Fuller re. World Game & UNU & others (Box 6, Folder 248)
  - re. DSI & United Nations University & World Game (Box 6, Folder 249)
  - Proposed YPO fund raising letter re. World Game (Box 6, Folder 250)
  - Memo re. UNU (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - Letter from R.B. Fuller to N. Kaiser re. McGuire House & reply (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - Letter from J. Harr to N. Kaiser re. ARBA funding (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - Letter from N. Kaiser to R.B. Fuller re. foundation structure (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Minutes of December 10, 1977 DSI Board meeting (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - re. minutes of Design Science Institute meeting (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to R.B. Fuller re. floating breakwater (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Agenda for, & minutes of, DSI meeting in Philadelphia (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - DSI form BSW - 497 (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - "Bucky Fuller & the Final Exam" - article in Sunday NY Times (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - re. Bucky's role in DSI (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - Ad for video seminar on Design Science (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - Photos of "Rowing Needles" (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Letter from G. Olds to DSI re. meeting in January 1976 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Syncon 76 brochure (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Original doodles re. Synergetic Geometry (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Letters from W. Wolf to R. Shelton & response re. Harvard Degree for R.B. Fuller (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Letter from G. Anselericius to W. Wolf re. Harvard Degree for R.B. Fuller (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Notice of meeting (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Design Science Institute meeting agenda (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - World Game invitation (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - R.B. Fuller & EST Foundation (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Saturday Evening Post: "Fifty Years Ahead of My Time" (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Washington Post article re. R.B. Fuller & W. Erhard (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Harvard Faculty Directory (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - NY Times re. Bubble over Winooski, Vermont (Box 6, Folder 276)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute order form (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - World Game brochure (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Wall Street Journal article re. video tapes - 43 hours (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - R.B. Fuller video seminar brochure (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to S. Sadao re. R.B. Fuller (Box 6, Folder 281)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to C. Haar re. R.B. Fuller (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - World Game ads (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - R.B. Fuller obituary (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - Bucky & Ann death notice (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Anne Fuller death notice (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Notes re. Buckminster Fuller Institute founding (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Letter & memo from D. Richter to W. Wolf re. Buckminster Fuller Institute (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to H. Meyer re. D. Richter letter (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute newsletter vol. 1 (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute newsletter vol. 1 no. 7 (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - Letter from R. Snyder to W. Wolf & ad re. video (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute newsletter vol. 1 no. 8 (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute brochure (Box 7, Folder 294)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute artifact ad (Box 7, Folder 295)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute letter (Box 7, Folder 296)
  - Letter from J. Snyder to W. Wolf re. Buckminster Fuller Institute startup (Box 7, Folder 297)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute newsletter vol. 2 no. 1 (Box 7, Folder 298)
  - Letter from S. Sharkey to W. Wolf re. Bucky's drawings & photos (Box 7, Folder 299)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to P. Hyde re. Buckminster Fuller Institute (Box 7, Folder 300)
  - Letter from R. Whaley to W. Wolf re. DSI demise (Box 7, Folder 301)
  - Letter re. Buckminster Fuller Institute startup (Box 7, Folder 302)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute newsletter vol. 2 no. 6 (Box 7, Folder 303)
  - Buckminster Fuller Institute newsletter vol. 2 (Box 7, Folder 304)
  - Trim Tab vol. 3 no. 2 (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - Notes re. Buckminster Fuller Institute startup (Box 7, Folder 306)
  - Letters of recommendation from W. Wolf to A. Edmondson (Box 7, Folder 307)
  - Trim Tab vol. 3 no. 4 (Box 7, Folder 308)
  - Dymaxion Artifacts catalog (Box 7, Folder 309)
  - Trim Tab vol. 4 no. 1 (Box 7, Folder 310)
  - "The Buckminster Fuller Design Science Center" (Box 7, Folder 311)
  - "Trim Tab" - bulletin of Buckminster Fuller Institute (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Invitation to R.B. Fuller's drawing exhibit (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - Ad re. geometry workshop (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Trim Tab vol. 4 no. 3 (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Letters & memos from W. Wolf to D. Moore re. Buckminster Fuller Institute startup (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - NY Times: "A Little House on the Prairie Goes to a Museum" (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - Floating breakwater patent text filing with USPTO (Box 7, Folder 1001)
  - Registrants at floating breakwater conference (Box 7, Folder 1002)
  - MIT Sea grant report on summer lab (Box 7, Folder 1003)
  - Letter from J. Colonell to W. Wolf including resume (Box 7, Folder 1004)
  - Letter from D. Wyman to W. Wolf re. floating breakwater proposals (Box 7, Folder 1005)
  - US Patent No. 3,863,455 - floating breakwater (Box 7, Folder 1006)
  - Harper's Article re. Synergetics (Box 7, Folder 1007)
  - BF Goodrich initial contact (Box 7, Folder 1008)
  - Two letters from M. Hare to R.B. Fuller (Box 7, Folder 1009)
  - Letter from L. del Olmo to R.B. Fuller re. breakwater (Box 7, Folder 1010)
  - Meeting notes - R.B. Fuller and W. Wolf (Box 7, Folder 1011)
  - Letters and cable from R. Bucalo to R.B. Fuller re. breakwaters (Box 7, Folder 1012)
  - Letter from V. Smythe to W. Wolf re. floating breakwater (Box 7, Folder 1013)
  - Student report on floating breakwater (Box 7, Folder 1014)
  - Maine Maritime floating breakwater dev. including sketch (Box 7, Folder 1015)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to E. Tedeschi re. Popular Science Article (Box 7, Folder 1016)
  - Note from S. Sharkey to W. Wolf re. breakwater (Box 7, Folder 1017)
  - Bridgeport Post article re. University of Rhode Island effort (Box 7, Folder 1018)
  - Letter from V. Smythe to R.B. Fuller re. Popular Science article (Box 7, Folder 1019)
  - Notes from meeting - R.B. Fuller, E. Tedeschi, T. Sutton, W. Wolf (Box 7, Folder 1020)
  - Phone call re. Akron (Box 7, Folder 1021)
  - Correspondence with Brother Chuala (Box 7, Folder 1022)
  - Popular Science article re. patent (Box 7, Folder 1023)
  - Popular Science article using old tires (Box 7, Folder 1024)
  - Marine Tech Society 8th Annual Art. re. long range planning (Box 7, Folder 1025)
  - BF Goodrich Sea Boom (oil containment) brochure (Box 7, Folder 1026)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to J Castle re. breakwater (Box 7, Folder 1027)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to R. Armada re. breakwater (Box 7, Folder 1028)
  - Letter of thanks from S. Sharkey to W. Wolf (Box 7, Folder 1029)
  - R.B. Fuller Itineraries (Box 7, Folder 1030)
  - Letters from W. Wolf to US Embassy re. Abidjan cable (Box 7, Folder 1031)
  - Notes re. floating breakwaters (Box 7, Folder 1032)
  - N. Kaiser witnessed R.B. Fuller drawings (Box 7, Folder 1033)
  - Proposed initial agreement (Box 7, Folder 1034)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to R.B. Fuller asking RBF not to sign & letter from E. Tedeschi (Box 7, Folder 1035)
  - Letters from T. Carmel to R.B. Fuller re. SID interest (Box 7, Folder 1036)
  - Letter from R.B. Fuller to W. Wolf re. U Shaped Boom (Box 7, Folder 1037)
  - re. BF Goodrich agreement (Box 7, Folder 1038)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to V. Smythe re. BF Goodrich agreement (Box 7, Folder 1039)
  - Letter from W. Wolf to E. Tedeschi re. U shape inclusion in R.B. Fuller patent (Box 7, Folder 1040)
  - Letter from V. Smythe to W. Wolf re. BF Goodrich agreement (Box 7, Folder 1041)
  - Initially proposed agreement with BF Goodrich (Box 7, Folder 1042)